{"Topic": "Microorganisms", "Subject": "General Knowledge", "Data": [{"Question": "Of all micro-organisms, the most adaptable and versatile are -", "op1": "Viruses", "op2": "Bacteria", "op3": "Algae", "op4": "Fungi", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Mycology is the study of \u2013", "op1": "Bacteria", "op2": "Fungi", "op3": "Insects", "op4": "Parasites", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "The shape of coccus bacteria is generally \u2013", "op1": "Spherical", "op2": "Rod like", "op3": "Comma shaped", "op4": "Spiral", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Viruses that infect bacteria are called \u2013", "op1": "Methanogens", "op2": "Pathogens", "op3": "Lichens", "op4": "Bacteriophages", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Baltimore system is used to classify \u2013", "op1": "Viruses", "op2": "Bacteria", "op3": "Fungi", "op4": "Protozoa", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Spirogyra is a type of", "op1": "Bacteria", "op2": "Virus", "op3": "Algae", "op4": "Fungi", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "A lichen is a composite organism consisting of \u2013", "op1": "Algae & Bacteria", "op2": "Bacteria & Virus", "op3": "Virus &Fungi", "op4": "Algae & Fungi", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which of these is an autotroph?", "op1": "Cuscuta", "op2": "Algae", "op3": "Bacteria", "op4": "Mushroom", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Rhizobium, the organism found in root nodules of legumes are \u2013", "op1": "Bacteria", "op2": "Fungi", "op3": "Lichen", "op4": "Algae", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Organisms which take in nutrients from dead and decaying matter are called \u2013", "op1": "Autotrophs", "op2": "Heterotrophs", "op3": "Saprotrophs", "op4": "Autoheterotrophs", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "The shape of Bacillus bacteria is generally \u2013", "op1": "Spherical", "op2": "Comma shaped", "op3": "Rod like", "op4": "Spiral", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Who discovered the process of fermentation?", "op1": "Edward Jenner", "op2": "Louis Pasteur", "op3": "Jonas Salk", "op4": "William Harvey", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Rhizobium bacteria are present in the _____ of leguminous plants.", "op1": "Roots", "op2": "Leaves", "op3": "Fruits", "op4": "Flowers", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which of these is a saprotroph?", "op1": "Algae", "op2": "Pitcher plant", "op3": "Fungi", "op4": "Cuscuta", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Prokaryotes do not have \u2013", "op1": "Cytoplasm", "op2": "Ribosome", "op3": "Nuclear membrane", "op4": "Chromosomes", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Which of the following does not have the capacity to reproduce outside the host cell?", "op1": "Bacteria", "op2": "Fungi", "op3": "Algae", "op4": "Virus", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "What type of microorganism is yeast which is used in many food preparations?", "op1": "Bacteria", "op2": "Fungi", "op3": "Algae", "op4": "Virus", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Pencillium from which an antibiotic is obtained is a type of \u2013", "op1": "Bacteria", "op2": "Virus", "op3": "Algae", "op4": "Fungus", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "The sole members of kingdom Monera are \u2013", "op1": "Mushrooms", "op2": "Virus", "op3": "Algae", "op4": "Bacteria", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Litmus used as an indicator for acids and bases is extracted from \u2013", "op1": "Lichens", "op2": "Virus", "op3": "Plants", "op4": "Bacteria", "Answer": 3}]}